<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rahriver</title>
    <link>https://rahriver.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rahriver</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:42:20 +0330</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rahriver.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abstract - Potential of Circulatory Cell-Free DNA</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_sle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:42:20 +0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_sle/</guid>
      <description>A Systematic Review on the Potential of Circulatory Cell-Free DNA in the Diagnosis of Systemic Lupus Erythematosus Patients Ramin Yousefpour Shahrivar1, Zahra Ahmadi Fakhr2, Zahra Jahanbakhsh3, Fatemeh Karami4 Abstract Background: Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) is one of the frequent autoimmune disorders which is characterized by production of auto-antibodies against different tissues and circulatory DNAs released from apoptotic bodies. Owing to the confusing and delayed diagnosis of SLE, demand for early biomarkers made me to assess the potential of circulatory cell free DNA (cfDNA) in the diagnosis of SLE patients through systematic review of the previously performed studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract - Detection of Chromosomal Abnormalities</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_aims/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:31:54 +0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_aims/</guid>
      <description>Detection of Major Structural Chromosomal Abnormalities in Human Karyotypes Using Convolutional Neural Networks Ramin Yousefpour Shahrivar1, Fatemeh Karami2 Abstract Background and aims: Chromosomal abnormalities are the prevalent cause of various types of genetic disorders, which can result in serious health problems. Identification of structural chromosomal abnormalities with high accuracy is essential for proper diagnosis and therapy. Therefore, it was aimed to create a machine learning model employing convolutional neural network (CNN) algorithms that can accurately identify major structural chromosomal anomalies in karyotype images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract   Smart Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_smart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:28:58 +0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_smart/</guid>
      <description>Smart Lipid-Based Nanoparticles in Lung Cancer Treatment: Current Status and Future Directions Abstract Lung cancer remains the leading cause of cancer-related deaths worldwide, and conventional treatments for the disease often fall short. Smart nanoparticles (NPs) are emerging as a promising strategy for the treatment of lung cancer, owing to their ability to selectively deliver therapeutic agents to cancer cells while minimizing off-target effects. Smart NPs can respond to specific stimuli such as changes in pH, temperature, or enzymes, allowing them to release their cargo only when triggered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract - Enhancing Fetal Anomaly Detection</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 13:19:38 +0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/abs_ml/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing Fetal Anomaly Detection in US Images: A Review of Machine Learning-Based Approaches Ramin Yousefpour Shahrivar1, Fatemeh Karami2, Ebrahim Karami3 Abstract Fetal development is a critical phase, and timely identification of anomalies in ultrasound images is vital for the health of the unborn child and the mother. Medical imaging has been crucial in detecting fetal abnormalities and malformations during prenatal diagnosis. Despite advances in ultrasound technology, accurately detecting irregularities in prenatal images remains challenging, often requiring significant time and expertise from medical professionals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primer Design</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/primer_design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 02:17:43 +0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/primer_design/</guid>
      <description>Why Do We Design Primers? Primers are short (usually 18-27 bp), single-stranded DNA sequences that are complementary to the target DNA sequence. They are essential components in the Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) process, which amplifies a specific fragment of DNA. The main reasons why we design primers for PCR are:
1.Specificity: Primers ensure that only the region of interest is amplified and not other regions with similar sequences. Specific primers improve the accuracy of PCR and reduce false-positive results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My DESeq2 Workflow</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/deseq2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 19:07:04 +0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/posts/deseq2/</guid>
      <description>Differential Gene Expression I use this code to run DESeq2 for evey differential gene expression analysis I have:
library(DESeq2) library(biomaRt) library(DEGreport) library(ggplot2) library(dplyr) # Load data setwd(&amp;#39;/home/&amp;lt;directory&amp;gt;&amp;#39;) cts &amp;lt;- read.delim(&amp;#39;counts_data.csv&amp;#39;, sep=&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;, header = TRUE, row.names = 1) condition &amp;lt;- factor(c(&amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;)) coldata &amp;lt;- data.frame(row.names = colnames(cts), condition) Groups &amp;lt;- make.names(c(&amp;#34;Control&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Disease&amp;#34;)) keep &amp;lt;- rowSums(cts &amp;gt;= 10) &amp;gt;= min(table(coldata)) cts &amp;lt;- cts[keep, ] dds &amp;lt;- DESeqDataSetFromMatrix(countData = round(cts), colData = coldata, design = ~condition) dds &amp;lt;- DESeq(dds) # Save all the results res &amp;lt;- results(dds, contrast = c(&amp;#34;condition&amp;#34;, Groups[2], Groups[1]), alpha = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Gallery</title>
      <link>https://rahriver.github.io/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rahriver.github.io/gallery/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
